<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TFT LCD on TFT Display Technology</title><link>https://tft-display.net/tags/tft-lcd/</link><description>Recent content in TFT LCD on TFT Display Technology</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tft-display.net/tags/tft-lcd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Resolution and Aspect Ratio</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/resolution-aspect-ratio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/resolution-aspect-ratio/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="understanding-resolution-and-aspect-ratio-in-tft-lcd-displays">Understanding Resolution and Aspect Ratio in TFT LCD Displays&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When designing or selecting a TFT LCD for an embedded product, two critical technical parameters to understand are &lt;strong>resolution&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>aspect ratio&lt;/strong>. These factors greatly influence user experience, image clarity, UI layout, and even performance in embedded systems such as HMI panels, control terminals, or smart IoT devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article explores both concepts in depth, helping developers and engineers make informed choices when specifying displays for industrial and consumer applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is TFT LCD?</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/what-is-tft-lcd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/what-is-tft-lcd/</guid><description>&lt;p>TFT LCD (Thin-Film Transistor Liquid Crystal Display) is a sophisticated display technology used extensively across modern electronics. From smartphones and tablets to factory HMIs and medical monitors, TFT LCDs form the visual interface of countless devices. This article presents an in-depth look at TFT LCD technology—its working principle, structure, advantages, variants, and applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-tft-lcd-technology">Introduction to TFT LCD Technology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>TFT LCDs belong to the family of active-matrix displays. Each pixel is coupled with a thin-film transistor, enabling independent and accurate control of image rendering. This technology surpasses passive matrix displays in speed, contrast, and overall quality.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>