<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on TFT Display Technology</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on TFT Display Technology</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tft-display.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backlight Design &amp; Driver Circuits for TFT LCD Displays</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/backlight-design-driver-circuits/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/backlight-design-driver-circuits/</guid><description>&lt;p>A &lt;strong>TFT LCD&lt;/strong> relies on a backlight to illuminate its pixels, enabling the display to produce a visible image. Without a backlight, the LCD layer would simply modulate light from an external source and appear dark in most applications. If you’re not yet familiar with how TFT displays are structured, it’s worth reviewing &lt;a href="https://tft-display.net/posts/what-is-tft-lcd/">What is TFT LCD&lt;/a> for an introduction to panel layers and light modulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="how-tft-lcd-backlights-work">How TFT LCD Backlights Work&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most modern TFT LCDs use &lt;strong>LED-based backlight systems&lt;/strong>. The LEDs can be placed along the panel edges (edge-lit) or behind the LCD (direct-lit). Their light passes through:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FPC Layout and Pin Mapping for TFT LCD Modules</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/fpc-layout-and-pin-mapping/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/fpc-layout-and-pin-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;p>In embedded display design, &lt;strong>FPC layout&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>pin mapping&lt;/strong> are often underestimated but are absolutely critical for ensuring reliable performance and long-term stability. The FPC — short for &lt;em>Flexible Printed Circuit&lt;/em> — acts as the bridge between the TFT LCD panel and the mainboard, carrying high-speed data, control signals, and power lines in a compact, flexible form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A well-designed FPC ensures:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Signal integrity&lt;/strong> for high-speed interfaces like LVDS or MIPI-DSI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Electromagnetic compatibility&lt;/strong> in noisy industrial environments.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mechanical durability&lt;/strong> for long product lifetimes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ease of manufacturing and assembly&lt;/strong> during mass production.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In this guide, we will go step-by-step through &lt;strong>best practices for FPC layout&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>how to define pin mapping&lt;/strong> for different types of TFT LCD modules.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MIPI vs LVDS vs RGB: Choosing the Right TFT LCD Interface</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/mipi-vs-lvds-vs-rgb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/mipi-vs-lvds-vs-rgb/</guid><description>&lt;p>When integrating a TFT LCD module into an embedded system, &lt;strong>choosing the right display interface&lt;/strong> is one of the first and most important decisions. The interface determines:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How data is transmitted between the main processor and the display.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The achievable resolution, refresh rate, and color depth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Power consumption, EMI performance, and cable length tolerance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Three of the most common interfaces in industrial and embedded designs are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>MIPI-DSI (Mobile Industry Processor Interface – Display Serial Interface)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>LVDS (Low Voltage Differential Signaling)&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>RGB Parallel Interface&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This guide provides a detailed comparison of &lt;strong>MIPI vs LVDS vs RGB&lt;/strong>, explaining how each works, their strengths, weaknesses, and the scenarios where they perform best.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resolution and Aspect Ratio</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/resolution-aspect-ratio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/resolution-aspect-ratio/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="understanding-resolution-and-aspect-ratio-in-tft-lcd-displays">Understanding Resolution and Aspect Ratio in TFT LCD Displays&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When designing or selecting a TFT LCD for an embedded product, two critical technical parameters to understand are &lt;strong>resolution&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>aspect ratio&lt;/strong>. These factors greatly influence user experience, image clarity, UI layout, and even performance in embedded systems such as HMI panels, control terminals, or smart IoT devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article explores both concepts in depth, helping developers and engineers make informed choices when specifying displays for industrial and consumer applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TN vs IPS vs VA: A Comprehensive Comparison of LCD Panel Technologies</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/tn-vs-ip-vs-va/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/tn-vs-ip-vs-va/</guid><description>&lt;p>When selecting a TFT LCD for a consumer product, industrial control system, or embedded device, understanding the difference between TN, IPS, and VA panel technologies is crucial. Each offers unique strengths and trade-offs in terms of viewing angles, color accuracy, response time, and cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article compares TN, IPS, and VA technologies in depth, helping developers, product designers, and display engineers choose the right panel type for their specific applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is TFT LCD?</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/what-is-tft-lcd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/what-is-tft-lcd/</guid><description>&lt;p>TFT LCD (Thin-Film Transistor Liquid Crystal Display) is a sophisticated display technology used extensively across modern electronics. From smartphones and tablets to factory HMIs and medical monitors, TFT LCDs form the visual interface of countless devices. This article presents an in-depth look at TFT LCD technology—its working principle, structure, advantages, variants, and applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-tft-lcd-technology">Introduction to TFT LCD Technology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>TFT LCDs belong to the family of active-matrix displays. Each pixel is coupled with a thin-film transistor, enabling independent and accurate control of image rendering. This technology surpasses passive matrix displays in speed, contrast, and overall quality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trends in IoT SBCs</title><link>https://tft-display.net/posts/iot-sbc-trends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tft-display.net/posts/iot-sbc-trends/</guid><description>&lt;p>What’s new in IoT-focused SBC design and deployment strategies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>